# Hämäläinen Aleksi

aleksi.jonathan.hamalainen@gmail.com | +358 40 654 0297

## **ABOUT ME**

For the last two years, I have focused on building a theoretical base in the field of intelligent systems. Aug 2018 - Present | Helsinki, Finland Now, I am looking for a job in the field. On my free time, I go fishing, hiking, or attend a triathlon.

## **EDUCATION**

## **AALTO UNIVERSITY**

M.Sc. Machine Learning and Data Minina

April 2019 | Helsinki, Finland

GPA: 4.5 / 5.0 Minor: Robotics

#### **TSINGHUA UNIVERSITY**

Tsinghua International Summer School: Deep Learning July 2017 | Beijing, China

## **AALTO UNIVERSITY**

B.Sc. Industrial Engineering and Management Nov 2017 | Helsinki, Finland

GPA: 4.1 / 5.0

Minor: Computer Science

## LINKS

Github:// gamleksi LinkedIn:// aleksi-hamalainen

# **SKILLS**

Experienced:

Python • C++ • Matlab • ROS MuJoCo • Simulink • PvTorch TensorFlow • Ubuntu • MacOs Familiar:

Scala • Javascript • OpenCv • React MySQL • C • Cuda • Blender • XML

# COURSEWORK

- Computational inverse problems
- Bayesian Data Analysis
- Deep Learning
- Digital and Optimal Control
- Non-linear Filtering and Parameter Estimation
- Manipulation, Decision Making and Learning in Robotics
- Programming Parallel Computers
- Euclidean Spaces

## **EXPERIENCE**

## INTELLIGENT ROBOTICS GROUP, AALTO UNIVERSITY

| Msc Thesis worker / Research Intern

I have developed a machine learning model, that can perform based on image data a robotic manipulation task in the real world. With domain randomization and behavioral cloning, the system can be solely taught in a simulation, from which the learned model can be transferred into a real environment. I have conducted the entire pipeline from building the simulation to demonstrating successful results in a real environment. Technologies, such as ROS, Movelt!, OpenCv, MuJoCo, and PyTorch are used. This work will be submitted to IROS.

## INTELLIGENT ROBOTICS GROUP | Research Intern

May 2018 - Jul 2018 | Helsinki, Finland

I conducted a domain randomization method for affordance detection for a robotic manipulation task. The method was developed with Blender, a 3D computer graphics software. A target environment was first modeled with Blender. Images of the environment and their respective affordance labeled images were rendered. Properties, such as textures, positions, shape, scale of objects in the environment were randomized for each image.

## JUNCTION HACKATHON | Board member

Jan 2017 - Present | Helsinki, Finland

Junction hackathon functions as an independent company since January 2017. Junction has developed into an international hackathon organized in Finland, Japan, Vietnam, China, Hungary, and Saudi Arabia.

#### **AALTO ENTREPRENEURSHIP SOCIETY** | President

Jan 2016 - Dec 2016 | Helsinki, Finland

Aaltoes is Europe's most active entrepreneurship society, and, as a key player in European startup scene, it has founded Slush and Junction. As president, I was responsible for team building, strategy, and growth. We organized Junction hackathon for the second time, and scaled the event to 1500 participants from 70 countries, which resulted in a world-class hackathon. I got selected to the list of top 100 information technology influencers in Finland: the list in Finnish.

#### **JUNCTION HACKATHON** | Head of Participants

Jun 2015 - Dec 2015 | Helsinki, Finland

I gathered 500 participants from 30 countries for the first Junction hackathon.

## **PROJECTS**

## IMITATION LEARNING FOR AN RC CAR

A hackathon project, where an RC car agent imitates driving on a track based on gathered driving data. The behavioral model was inspired by Nvidia...

#### SELF-SUPERVISED LEARNING FROM VIDEO

Replication of the model in *Time-Contrastive Networks: Self-Supervised* Learning from Video for a manipulation task in a simulation. Link to the project.

#### **PATH TRACER**

A course project built with C++, where I developed a data structure accelerator and parallelization for the path tracer. Link to the project.

#### REGISTRATION SYSTEM FOR JUNCTION

A registration platform for 1500 participants built with React and Express for Junction 2016. Link to the project.